A Guide to the Papers of the Conservation Council of Virginia, 1972, and 1986-1996
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Conservation Council of Virginia, 1972, and 1986-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9883-f
The collection contains ca. 2,000 items (12 Hollinger boxes, ca. 5 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Nancy Summers, Richmond, Virginia, on July 14, 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Conservation Council of Virginia was formed in 1969 as a decentralized coalition of approximately forty Virginia environmental groups whose main purpose was to act as an organizing agency for the participating groups in lobbying for common state environmental goals.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of the Conservation Council of Virginia contains ca. 2,000 items (12 Hollinger boxes, ca. 5 linear feet), 1972, and 1986-1996, consisting of three types of records: 1) organizational records, which include minutes, correspondence, by-laws, financial statements, membership lists, newsletters, news clippings, research reports, and printed materials; 2) topical files concerning environmental issues and the positions of the Conservation Council of Virginia; and 3) ad hoc advisory group records.
Organization
The collection is organized alphabetically by file name within each of three series and in reverse chronological order within each folder.
Series I: Organizational Records (Boxes 1-5)
Series II: Topical Files (Boxes 5-10)
Series III: Ad hoc advisory groups (Boxes 10-12)
Contents List
- Organizational Records
  - Board of Directors Meetings 1987-1994, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - By-laws and Articles of Incorporation 1986-1994 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1987-1992 Apr, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1992 May - 1994, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Financial Papers 1988-1994, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Meetings 1988-1990 Apr 7, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Meetings 1990 Aug 4 - 1994, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Meeting Notices 1986-1994 (Box 4)
  - Membership Lists - Associate Organizations 1989-1993 (Box 4)
  - Membership Lists - Individual & Board of Directors 1988-1992 (Box 4)
  - Membership Lists - Voting Organizations 1990 - 1993 (Box 4)
  - Newsletters 1986-1994, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - "Some Comments on the Founding & Functioning of the Conservation Council of Virginia" by Robert T. Dennis 1972 Mar (Box 5)
  - Tax Information 1991-1996, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Treasurer's Reports 1990-1994, 2 folders (Box 5)
- Topical Files
  - Conference re: Air Quality & Energy Policy in Virginia, held on September 26, 1992 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Land Use Strategy Group 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - Medical Waste Incineration 1991-1992, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Medical Waste Incineration 1993-1996, 6 folders (Box 7)
  - National Park Service - Air Quality 1991 Jan-Mar (Box 7)
  - National Park Services - Air Quality 1991 Apr - 1992 Aug, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - National Park Service - Air Quality 1992 Sep - 1995, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - National Park Service - Finding of Adverse Impact on Air Quality in Shenandoah National Park 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - National Park Service - Shenandoah National Park Coalition 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - Nontidal Wetlands Strategy Group 1989-1993, 4 folders (Box 10)
- Ad Hoc Advisory Groups
  - Ad Hoc Advisory Group on Acid Rain Operating Permits 1992 - 1994 Sep, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Ad Hoc Advisory Group on Acid Rain Operating Permits 1994 Oct - 1996, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Ad Hoc Advisory Group Concerning New and Modified Stationary Source Permits 1990-1992, n.d., 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Ad Hoc Advisory Group Concerning New and Modified Stationary Source Permits - Documents 1993-1994, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Ad Hoc Advisory Group Concerning Operating Permits for Stationary Sources - Title V 1992-1994, 2 folders (Box 12)